<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="wlr_foreign_toplevel_management_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2018 Ilia Bozhinov

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING
    OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS
    SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_manager_v1" version="3">
    <description summary="list and control opened apps">
      The purpose of this protocol is to enable the creation of taskbars
      and docks by providing them with a list of opened applications and
      letting them request certain actions on them, like maximizing, etc.
    </description>

    <event name="toplevel">
      <description summary="a toplevel surface was created">
        A new toplevel handle was created.
      </description>
      <arg name="toplevel" type="new_id" interface="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1"/>
    </event>

    <event name="finished">
      <description summary="the compositor has finished with the manager">
        This event indicates that the compositor is done sending events
        to the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_manager_v1. The server will destroy
        the object immediately after sending this request, so it will
        become invalid and the client should free any resources associated
        with it.
      </description>
    </event>

    <request name="stop">
      <description summary="stop sending events">
        Indicates the client no longer wishes to receive events for new toplevels.
        However the compositor may emit further toplevel_created events, until
        the finished event is emitted.

        The client must not send any more requests after this one.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1" version="3">
    <description summary="an opened toplevel">
      A zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object represents an opened toplevel
      window. Each app may have multiple opened toplevels.
    </description>

    <event name="title">
      <description summary="title change">
        The title of the toplevel has changed.
      </description>
      <arg name="title" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="app_id">
      <description summary="app-id change">
        The app-id of the toplevel has changed.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="output_enter">
      <description summary="output enter">
        This event is emitted when the toplevel becomes visible on the given output.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </event>

    <event name="output_leave">
      <description summary="output leave">
        This event is emitted when the toplevel stops being visible on the given output.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </event>

    <enum name="state">
      <description summary="types of states on the toplevel">
        The different states that a toplevel can have. These have the same semantics
        as the states with the same names defined in xdg-toplevel.
      </description>
      <entry name="maximized"  value="0" summary="the toplevel is maximized"/>
      <entry name="minimized"  value="1" summary="the toplevel is minimized"/>
      <entry name="activated"  value="2" summary="the toplevel is active"/>
      <entry name="fullscreen" value="3" summary="the toplevel is fullscreen"/>
    </enum>

    <event name="state">
      <description summary="the toplevel's state changed">
        The states of the toplevel have changed. The given state is the
        new state. The received state can be set as an array of uint32.
      </description>
      <arg name="state" type="array"/>
    </event>

    <event name="done">
      <description summary="all information about the toplevel has been sent">
        This event is sent after all changes in the toplevel state have been
        sent. This allows changes to the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1
        properties to be seen as atomic, even if they happen via multiple events.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="closed">
      <description summary="this toplevel has been destroyed">
        The compositor sends this event to indicate that the
        zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 will no longer receive events and
        should be destroyed.
      </description>
    </event>

    <request name="set_maximized">
      <description summary="requests that the toplevel be maximized">
        Requests that the toplevel be maximized.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_maximized">
      <description summary="requests that the toplevel be unmaximized">
        Requests that the toplevel be unmaximized.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_minimized">
      <description summary="requests that the toplevel be minimized">
        Requests that the toplevel be minimized.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_minimized">
      <description summary="requests that the toplevel be unminimized">
        Requests that the toplevel be unminimized.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="activate">
      <description summary="activate the toplevel">
        Request that this toplevel be activated on the given seat.
        The compositor may or may not honor this request.
      </description>
      <arg name="seat" type="object" interface="wl_seat"/>
    </request>

    <request name="close">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be closed">
        Send a request to the toplevel to close itself.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_rectangle">
      <description summary="the rectangle which represents the toplevel">
        The rectangle of the surface specified in this request corresponds
        to the place where the app using this protocol represents the given
        toplevel. It can be used by the compositor as a hint for animations.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="x"       type="int"/>
      <arg name="y"       type="int"/>
      <arg name="width"   type="int"/>
      <arg name="height"  type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object">
        Destroys the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object.
        This request should be called either when the client does not want to
        use the toplevel anymore or after the closed event has been received to
        finalize the destruction of the object.
      </description>
    </request>

    <!-- version 2 -->
    <event name="parent" since="2">
      <description summary="parent change">
        This event is emitted whenever the parent of the toplevel changes.
      </description>
      <arg name="parent" type="object" interface="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1" allow-null="true"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
